我叫巴里·艾倫
My name is Barry Allen.
是現今世上速度最快的人
I am the fastest man alive.
我十一歲時  我母親被殺了
When I was 11, my mother was murdered.
我看到一道閃電
I saw a ball of lightning.
那里面  有個人
Inside the lightning there was a man.
他殺了我媽媽
He killed my mom.
我發誓這不是我干的
I swear to God I didn't do this.
-媽媽呢  -那晚發生的事讓人無法相信
- Where's mom? - What happened that night was impossible.
但是一場事故讓我也變得令人難以置信
Then an accident made me the impossible.
你陷入了昏迷
You were in a coma.
-昏迷了多久  -九個月
- For how long? - Nine months.
你的肌肉應該萎縮了
Your muscles should be atrophied,
但是卻在進行細胞重生
but instead they're in a state of cellular regeneration.
我不是唯一一個受爆炸影響的  是不是
I wasn't the only one affected, was I?
我們一直在尋找其他像你一樣的超能力者
We've been searching for other meta humans like yourself.
我一直想更加有所作為
All my life I've wanted to do more.
然后我搞砸了我第一次幫助別人的機會
And the first chance I get to help someone, I screw up.
你所做的好事會遠比這些錯事更有意義
The good you do must far outweigh the bad.
你不會再在里面待太久了
You're not gonna be in here much longer.
不管殺害媽媽的兇手是誰
Whoever killed mom,
我總算有辦法找到他們了
I think I finally have a way to find them.
到這部分我好像應該
This is the part where I'm supposed
做自我介紹了
to do the whole intro thingy.
巴里·艾倫  現今世上速度最快的人
Barry Allen, fastest man alive...
但是這個大家應該都知道了
But you know all that already.
那好  我們就去做點好事吧
All right, let's get to the good stuff.
你看到那里的煙了嗎  那是
You see that smoke? That's a fire
中城鬧市區西街和第三大街處發生火災了
on Western and 3rd in downtown Central City.
還有這團疾馳殘影  是我正在趕往火災現場
And that blur? That's me on my way to it.
我現在時速是352英里
I'm going 352 miles an hour.
今天速度真是太慢了
And it's a slow day.
這里是52號云梯隊
This is Ladder 52.
還有兩分鐘才能到達火災現場
We're still at least two minutes out.
到時候建筑里的人會死的
People are gonna die in there.
我知道
I know.
巴里
Barry?
Barry!
怎么了  跑過了嗎
What? Did I miss it?
已經跑過大約六個街區了
You overshot by about six blocks.
怪我
My bad.
佩奇
Paige!
我女兒  有人看到我女兒了嗎
My daughter! Has anyone seen my daughter?
佩奇
Paige!
到了嗎
You there yet?
你干什么呢
What are you doing?
沒什么
Nothing.
你在跟誰說話
Who were you talking to?
-沒人啊  -你是在跟巴里說話吧
- No one. - Are you talking to Barry?
-誰  -巴里·艾倫
- Who? - Barry Allen?
被閃電擊中  昏迷了九個月
Struck by lighting? Was in a coma for nine months?
醒來之后能跑得比聲音傳播都快的那個人
Woke up being able to run faster than the speed of sound?
-記起來了嗎  -沒有
- Ring a bell? - No.
很久沒跟他說話了
Haven't talked to him.
西斯科  這里火勢很猛
Cisco, there's fire everywhere!
西斯科  你還在嗎
Cisco, are you still there?
媽媽
Mom?
Mommy!
媽媽
人都救出來了
Everybody's out.
還有什么吩咐嗎  西斯科
What else you got for me, Cisco?
巴里  我是凱特琳
Barry, it's Caitlin.
凱特琳啊
Hey, Caitlin.
你好啊
How's your day?
馬上回尖端科研實驗室
Get back to S.T.A.R. Labs. Now.
這就回去
On my way.
危險區域
閑人免進
你們倆都瘋了嗎
Have you both lost your minds?
你們以為自己是誰
Who do you think you are?
我負責眼觀六路耳聽八方  他負責跑步救人
Well, I'm the eyes and ears, and he's the feet.
一點都不好笑好嗎
This isn't funny.
你這樣會害死自己的
You could have gotten yourself killed.
你不能跟什么超音速消防員一樣
You can't be running around the city
去市里火災現場救人
like some supersonic fireman.
為什么不行
Why not?
我們不是說過了嗎  要用我的速度做好事
This is what we talked about: Me using my speed to do good.
我們說的是你來
We talked about you helping us contain
幫我們控制其他可能
other people who might have been affected
被粒子加速器爆炸影響到的人
by the particle accelerator explosion.
是去對付超能力者
Meta-humans.
除了克萊德·馬登  我們還沒找到別人
And aside from Clyde Mardon, we haven't found any.
這座城市的人仍然需要幫助
People in this city still need help.
我能幫他們
And I can help them.
我們能幫他們
We can help them.
你能說句話嗎
Will you please say something?
我覺得凱特琳的意思是
I think what Caitlin is saying,
她以這種獨特的生氣方式想說的是
in her own spectacularly angry way,
我們才剛開始理解
is that we are just beginning to understand
你身體的能力
what your body is capable of.
不是我跟你嘮叨  艾倫先生
Not to sound like a broken record, Mr. Allen...
我覺得還是謹慎克制為妙
I do caution restraint.
威爾斯博士
Dr. Wells...
你就是因為克制才取得現在的成就嗎
I doubt restraint is how you got to be the man you are today.
我現在是坐著輪椅被社會遺棄的人
In a wheelchair and a pariah.
正是因為缺少克制  我才落得如此下場
Lack of restraint is what made me these things.
量力而行
Know your limits.
你弄壞什么的時候
Don't expect me to patch you up
不要每次都指望我幫你
every time you break something.
你去救人的時候發生什么事了嗎
Hey, uh... anything happen out there today?
你衣服上的傳感器返回了
The sensors in the suit were kicking back
一些奇怪的遙感數據
some weird telemetry,
好像你的身體指數出現了幾秒的驟增
like your vitals spiked for a few seconds.
我感覺很好啊
Never felt better.
喬  一切都好嗎
Hey, Joe, everything all right?
好極了  我在案發現場
Great. I got a fresh crime scene...
有一具尸體
a dead body...
警探正在詢問目擊者
detectives interviewing witnesses...
黃色警戒線已經拉好了
Miles of that yellow tape stretched over everything.
只差一個人了  你猜是誰
I'm only missing one thing. Can you guess what that is?
我馬上就到
I'll be right there.
工作召喚我了
My day job beckons.
你覺得他要什么時候才會意識到
When do you think he'll realize
他沒換衣服
he didn't take his clothes?
罪犯們拿了幾把手槍跑了
Perp made off with a bunch of handguns,
至少有六把格洛克19型手槍
at least six Glock 19s.
還有額外的彈夾
Fitted with extra ammunition magazines.
看來有人要準備大干一場啊
Somebody's looking to do a whole lot of bad.
不好意思我來晚了
Hey, sorry I'm late.
給自己買了點秋裝啊  艾倫先生
Doing a little fall shopping, Mr. Allen?
我今早出來得太匆忙了  沒注意到
I was going so fast this morning, I didn't even notice.
我把監控錄像下載下來了
I downloaded the surveillance footage off the video camera.
看起來只有一個罪犯啊
Looks like only one perp.
人人影視
YYeTs.com
原創翻譯  雙語字幕
■
僅供學習 禁止用于任何商業盈利行為
更多影視更新
請登陸www.YYeTs.com
翻譯：圈圈 西西 Liv 青椒 Silence
翻譯：DustD 木淺薰 迷失_綻放
錄像上可能只有一個  但實際上有六個人
Footage may only show one, but it was six guys.
時間軸：信徒 薛定諤的貓 咭鵬鵬
看看這些痕跡  它們都交錯在一起
Look, the tracks. They're all crossing each other.
六種腳印  六把槍被盜
Six sets of footprints. Six guns stolen.
校對：Michael 小蘿莉  Liv  迷失_綻放
這應該是團伙作案
We should be looking for a crew.
后期：MythCreator  總監:  蘋果果
真奇怪
Weird.
他們穿的鞋  看起來都是一個鞋碼的
The shoes, it looks like they're all the same size.
我猜是男士的十碼
Men's tens, I'd guess.
和你的鞋碼一樣  隊長
Just like you, Captain.
不是說你是嫌犯  長官  我
Not that you're a suspect, sir. I--
中城警局
你一心多用的能力真是令人贊嘆
Your ability to multi-task is truly remarkable.
你總是能同時讓我  隊長  還有你自己
The way you can embarrass me, the Captain, and yourself
-都覺得難為情  -喬  我很抱歉
- all at the same time. - Joe, I'm sorry.
你就知道跟我說這句話
I'm starting to think "Joe, I'm sorry" is
我都覺得我的名字是"喬  我很抱歉"了
my actual name considering how often you say it to me.
我要處理的事情太多了
I'm dealing with a lot right now.
我知道你的境地
Look, I know you are.
相信我  我也一樣
Believe me, I'm dealing with it, too.
以前我的想法非常簡單
I've always had a very simple set of beliefs.
重力讓一切東西墜落  水把東西弄濕
Gravity makes things fall. Water makes things wet.
直到幾周前  我相信世界上跑得最快的人
And up until a few weeks ago, I believed
跑完一英里需要四分鐘
the fastest man could run a mile in four minutes.
而不是四秒鐘
Not four seconds.
我三秒就能跑完
I could do it in three.
好吧  無關信息
Not relevant.
你沒跟愛瑞絲說這些吧
You haven't said anything to Iris about all this, have you?
沒有  我答應過你  我說到做到
No, I made you a promise. I keep my promises.
繼續這么撒謊
Keep on lying like that,
你還會被閃電擊中的
you're liable to get struck by lightning again.
現在就去實驗室
Get up to the lab.
開始分析從槍械店拿回來的證據
Start processing the evidence from the gun store.
愛瑞絲  你好
Hey, Iris.
巴里又跑了
Did Barry run away again?
除非這個問題出現在你的家庭作業里
Unless that's one of your homework questions, little lady,
不然就不關你的事  小朋友
it's none of your business.
回你房間去吧
Go on back to your room.
我想見我爸爸
I want to see my dad.
巴里  我說了不行
I already said no, Barry.
他沒做那些事  他沒有傷害我媽媽
He didn't do those things. He didn't hurt my mom.
關于那晚我說的是真的  我看見了
I was there that night. I saw.
-當時有個男人  -我知道
- There was a man. - Yeah, I know.
我們已經談過這個了
We've gone through this already.
那我為什么不能見他
Then why can't I go see him?
因為我說了不可以
Because I said so.
你不是我爸爸  你無權告訴我該做什么
You're not my father! You can't tell me what to do!
現在  我是唯一一個關心你的成年人
Right now, I am the only adult that gives a damn
所以我能告訴你你該做什么
what happens to you, so yes, I can tell you what to do.
現在回你的房間去吧
Now go to your room.
我恨你
I hate you!
這都是你的錯
This is all of your fault.
我本來可以選修歐洲民俗學
I could have taken European folklore
來達到我的社會學要求  但我沒有
to cover my sociology requirement, but no.
你跟我說  "愛瑞絲  學新聞吧
You said, "Take journalism, Iris.
當記者最有趣了"
Reporters have all of the fun."
你猜怎么著  巴里  當記者一點趣都沒有
Guess what, Barry? Reporters have none of the fun.
新聞無聊死了  我現在好無聊
Journalism is boring. I'm bored.
都怪你  怎么了
I blame you. What?
你為什么這樣看著我
Why are you staring at me like that?
你看起來真美
You look really nice.
謝謝
Thanks.
你為什么不好好打扮一下
Why don't you look nice?
今天下午  西裝革履
This afternoon? Suit and tie?
學校要授予西蒙·斯塔格
The university is giving Simon Stagg...
-西蒙·斯塔格  -一個大獎
- Simon Stagg. - some big award.
-你答應我  -為了你的報道
- And you agreed... - To explain the science stuff
要給你解釋那些科學知識  我現在想起來了
for your article. It's all coming back to me now.
你要多久才能回家換衣服
How fast can you get home and change?
一會兒就好
Pretty fast.
你好  艾倫
Hey, Allen.
喬讓我過來看看你在處理
Joe asked me to see where you're at
槍械店證據的事情上進展到哪一步了
on the evidence from the gun store shooting.
你好  愛瑞絲
Oh, hey, Iris.
警探  你好
Detective.
得了  你們還是接吻吧
Please, guys, just kiss already.
記得嗎  我已經知道了
I already know, remember?
謝謝你表現得這么淡定  巴里
Thanks for being so cool about this, Barry.
我知道保守一個大秘密不容易
I know it's not easy keeping a big secret.
我正在習慣
I'm getting used to it.
我覺得挺不可思議的
I find it quite remarkable,
年度人物  感謝他為器官移植做出的貢獻
當年我還是中心城市大學
having once been a timid freshman
一名羞澀的大一新生
at Central City University,
現在我已經站在你們面前
to be standing before you now,
成為麗晶選擇獎的年度獲得者
the Regents Choice for man of the year.
雖然我很榮幸能夠接受這個獎項
While I very much appreciate the award,
但對我來說  真正的榮譽是知道
the real honor for me is knowing that
我在器官移植方面做的工作
my work in organ transference
能夠給予人們第二次生命的機會
helps give people a second chance at life.
非常謝謝你們的到來
Thank you all very much for coming.
好了  先說重要的
Okay. All right, first things first...
西蒙·斯塔格的細胞克隆工作
Simon Stagg's work in cellular cloning
為將來的器官替代學科
has led to huge advancements
帶來了巨大的進步
in the future of organ replacement...
記者在工作時可以喝酒嗎
Are journalists allowed to drink on the job?
好吧  如果你已經不耐煩了
Okay. If you are bored already,
還是得等到我們了解
just wait till we get to the science behind
細胞再生背后的科學
cellular regeneration.
真懷念這種感覺  巴里
I have missed this, Barry.
感覺我們自打你從昏迷中醒來
I feel like we haven't spent any quality time together
已經好久沒有這樣待在一起了
since you woke up from the coma.
是的  這幾周過得真瘋狂  我知道
Yeah, I've had a crazy few weeks, I know.
我覺得你因為艾迪總是在回避我
I thought maybe you'd been avoiding me because of Eddie.
我知道你認為我和老爸的搭檔約會并不好
I know you think it's wrong, me dating my dad's partner,
-我就是  -不
- and I just-- - No.
并不是這么回事
That is not it. At all.
斯塔格先生  我能否引用您的話
Mr. Stagg, I was wondering if I could get a quote
來為我的報道添色
from you for my article.
現在不行  小姐
Not now, miss.
我還是自己編點東西吧
I'll just make something up.
你要跟我說什么
So... what were you gonna tell me?
你看起來好像要說什么重要的事
You looked like you were about to say something.
沒錯...
Yeah--
安靜  所有人
Quiet down! All of you!
天吶
Oh, my god.
安靜
Quiet!
想得多周到啊
How considerate!
你們都戴著最昂貴的首飾
You're all wearing your finest jewelry!
好像知道我們要打劫你們一樣
Almost like you knew we were coming to rob you!
所有人排隊站好
Now everybody line up!
不要  不要
Don't. Don't.
不許動
Freeze!
放下武器
D-d-drop your weapons!
閃電俠
巴里
Barry.
Barry!
我轉過身來你就不見了
I turned around and you were gone.
發生什么事了  你沒事吧
What happened? Are you okay?
是的  我沒事
Yeah, yeah, I'm fine. I...
我跟著他們  想看清車牌
I went after them to try and get the plates.
-什么  -然后我就...
- Wha--? - And I...
我暈倒了
I fainted.
-你好  -愛瑞絲
- Hi. - Iris.
你們去哪了
Where were you?
爸爸  別緊張
Dad, go easy.
我在外面找到他的  他暈倒了
I found him outside. He fainted.
需要幫你找個醫護人員嗎  艾倫
You want me to get you a paramedic, Allen?
不用  我沒事  謝謝  艾迪
No, I'm fine. Thanks, Eddie.
我以為我死定了
I thought I was dead.
我看到子彈發射出來  然后就嘣一聲
I saw the gun go off, and then-- boom.
瞬間我就到外面了
Suddenly I'm outside.
我根本不知道是怎么到外面的
I have no idea how I got there.
你過來跟我談一下
Let me talk to you for a second.
好的
Yeah.
你去追那幾個劫匪了  是嗎
You chased those gunmen, didn't you?
是的  那幾個劫匪
Yeah, they must be the same guys
一定就是前幾天打劫槍店的人
that knocked over the gun shop earlier today.
如果你抓到他們了  打算怎么做
And what were you going to do when you caught them?
請求他們乖乖地停到路邊嗎
Ask them nicely to pull over?
你并不是刀槍不入
You're not bulletproof.
等等  你是嗎
Wait. Are you?
-不是  但是...  -那好
- No, but-- - Okay.
不許再逞英雄
No more heroics.
抓壞人不是你的工作
Chasing bad guys is not your job.
是我的工作  你不是警察
It's mine. You're not a cop.
跟我保證
Promise me.
我保證
Promise.
你知道愛瑞絲可不是傻子
And you know Iris is not stupid.
編點比"我暈倒了"更好一點的借口
Start making better excuses than "I fainted."
我...
I...
你騙了我們
You lied to us.
怎么不告訴我們你有陣發性暈眩呢
How could you not tell us you're experiencing dizzy spells?
我們是你的醫生
We're your doctors.
天知道你身體內到底怎么了
God knows what's going on inside your body.
你的細胞處在不斷變化當中
Your cells are in a constant state of flux.
你有可能會心肺衰竭
You could be experiencing cardiopulmonary failure
或者短暫性腦缺血
or a transient ischemic attack.
小中風  也可能不會
Mini stroke. Probably not.
在所有人當中你應該知道  科學要共享
You of all people should know that in science, we share.
我們之間不能有秘密
We do not keep secrets.
除了羅尼  還沒有別人讓她這么生氣
Wow... I haven't seen anyone make her that angry since Ronnie.
羅尼是凱特琳的未婚夫嗎
Ronnie was Caitlin's fiance?
加速器爆炸那晚死的那個嗎
The one that died the night of the accelerator explosion?
是的  他...
Yeah. He is...
失蹤了
missed.
現在...
Now...
我們看看你身上到底發生了什么
Let's figure out why this is happening to you.
尖端科研實驗室
我們都準備好了
We're all set.
做點預防措施  以防萬一
A little padding. Just in case.
好
Yeah.
你確定要這樣做嗎  西斯科
You're sure about this, Cisco?
大多數家用跑步機最大速度
Most home treadmills have a maximum speed of about
只能達到每小時12英里
12 miles per hour.
這個被西斯科改造了  相信我
This one has been Cisco'ed. Trust me.
它能承受你的速度
It can handle your speed.
好的
Okay.
心跳  血壓  神經傳導都很正常
Heart rate, blood pressure, nerve conduction all normal.
對巴里來說
For Barry.
腦電波在標準限額活動
Brainwave function within standard limits.
我說過這臺跑步機可以承受的
I told you the treadmill could take it.
凱特琳
Caitlin.
看他的血糖值
Look at the glucose levels.
天哪  這就說得通了
Oh, my god. Of course.
-對吧  -這么明顯
- Right? - It was so obvious.
血糖值  巴里
Glucose levels. Barry!
我們知道你為什么經常...
We think we know why you keep--
暈倒了
passing out.
警局
巴里
Barry!
殺妻案
諾拉·艾倫之死
巴里去哪里了
Where's Barry?
在洗澡
Taking a shower.
下午三點洗澡嗎
At three o'clock in the afternoon?
如果我上樓  會看到巴里·艾倫嗎
If I go up those stairs, am I gonna see Barry Allen?
或者你會因為撒謊而被禁足一周
Or are you gonna be grounded for a week for lying to me?
對不起  爸爸
I'm sorry, daddy.
別擔心  我知道他去哪里了
But don't worry. I know where he went.
我也知道
Me too.
我又暈倒了嗎
I passed out again?
急性低血糖
Total metabolic failure
導致的新陳代謝衰竭
brought on by acute hypoglycemia.
我吃得不夠
I'm not eating enough.
輸一袋葡萄糖就沒事了嗎
So an I.V. bag and I'm good to go?
四十袋還差不多
Try 40.
看來你是渴了
Guess you were thirsty.
我們得根據你的代謝變化
We're gonna need to fashion you a new diet
為你設計新的食譜
based on your metabolic changes.
我計算了一下  你需要進食
I've done a few calculations. You need to consume
將近850個墨西哥卷餅
an amount equal to roughly 850 tacos.
除非你直接吃牛油果蘸芝士
Unless we're talking cheese and guac,
那樣的話結果又會不同
which is like a whole other set of equations.
要想吃墨西哥菜  我推薦提托家
For Mexican, I recommend Tito's.
在布拉克納街
On Bruckner avenue?
他們家的玉米煎餅最棒了
Best burrito in the city.
韋斯特警探
Detective West.
你怎么會來尖端科研實驗室
What brings you to S.T.A.R. labs?
你不在你的實驗室
When I couldn't find you at your lab,
我就開始調查
I started doing a little research.
原來最近出了一位紅衣俠
Turns out there's been reports of a red streak around the city,
又是抗擊強盜  又是救火救人
stopping muggers, rescuing people from burning buildings.
你沒告訴他我們在合作嗎
You didn't tell him we were working together?
喬  我可以解釋
Joe, I can explain.
你在警察局已經有工作了  巴里
You already have a job in law enforcement, Barry.
我建議你回去專心工作
I suggest you get back to it.
別看我  我是支持你的
Don't look at me. I'm on your side.
警探
Detective.
我們都是為了巴里好
We all want what's best for Barry.
你要真是為了他好
If you wanted what was best for Barry,
就應該好好勸勸他
you'd try to talk him out of this lunacy
而不是放任他出去拿自己的命開玩笑
instead of encouraging him going out there risking his life.
你也看到了  有個人能控制天氣
You saw a man control the weather.
警方要怎么對付那樣的人
What are the police gonna do against someone like that?
那場爆炸事件之后
Since the accelerator explosion
我們懷疑還有類似他的人
we suspect there may be more like him.
你準備怎么做
And you're gonna do what?
抓他們嗎
Catch them?
你瘋了嗎
Are you insane?
你以為跑得快一點
You think because you can run real fast
就可以無敵了嗎  并不是
that you're invincible? You're not!
你還是個孩子
You're just a kid.
我的孩子
My kid.
我不是你的孩子  喬
I'm not your kid, Joe.
你也不是我父親
And you're not my father.
我爸爸正在經受牢獄之苦
My father's sitting in iron heights.
還抱著滿腹冤屈
Wrongfully convicted.
是你的判斷失誤
You were wrong about him.
這次你也判斷錯了
And you're wrong about this.
也許我沒能力幫他
Now I may not be able to help him,
但是如果我能從著火的大樓里救人
but if I can save someone from a burning building
或者阻止一些持槍歹徒  我一定會出手
or stop some armed thieves, I'm gonna do it.
你阻止不了我
And you can't stop me.
別白費力氣了
So don't try.
你覺得自己聰明無比
You think you're so smart.
你們都這樣
All of you.
但是有些事情你們根本不清楚
But you don't know what you don't know.
我希望你們能在發生死傷之前
And I hope that you're clever enough to figure it out
盡快想明白
before somebody gets killed.
你的其他同伴呢
Where's the rest of your crew?
只有我
Just me.
你要干什么  布萊克
What do you want, Black?
我的要求依舊只有一個
The only thing I still want in life...
讓你的老板死
Your boss dead.
你和你的隊伍動作太慢不能怪我
It's not my fault you and your team moved too slow.
我告訴你斯塔格在哪  可沒說會待多久
I told you where Stagg would be, not how long he'd be there.
我要知道他的全部行程
I need his full itinerary.
還有他辦公室和家里的安保權限
And security access to his office and home.
做夢
Screw you.
我在安保行業可是有名聲的
I've got a reputation in the security business.
我的老板被殺是一碼事
It's one thing if my employer gets iced.
在臥室里被殺就是另一碼事了
It's another if it happens in his bedroom.
你最好按我說的做  加瓦先生
You'll do what I ask, Mr. Java.
你沒有軍隊  能把我怎么樣
What the hell are you gonna do to me without your army?
我就是軍隊
I am an army.
警察局
你又要來沖我吼了嗎
Come to yell at me again?
西蒙·斯塔格的安保主管昨晚被殺
Simon Stagg's head of security was murdered last night.
法醫在現場收集了皮膚樣品
The coroner took some skin samples.
但愿是兇手的
Hopefully they belong to the killer.
看看有沒有匹配結果
See if you can find a match.
昨晚斯塔格的慈善晚宴遭到襲擊不是巧合
Can't be a coincidence that Stagg's benefit was attacked last night.
我這就去詢問斯塔格
I'm going to interview Stagg now.
-我跟你一起去  -你的工作在這里
- I'll come with you. - Your job is in here.
留下來搞定工作
Stay in here and do it.
-爸爸  -寶貝
- Hey, dad. - Hey, baby.
我要走了
Gotta go.
我爸為什么生你的氣
Why is my dad mad at you?
工作上的事
Work stuff.
你為什么生我的氣
Why are you mad at me?
我們本來要在吉特見面
You were supposed to meet me at Jitters
你要給我的文章提供一些科學背景資料
to give me some scientific background for my article.
結果我沒去
And I didn't show up.
現在我得在24小時之內拿出一篇新文章
And now I have to come up with a new article topic in 24 hours
不然我的任務就無法完成
or I fail the assignment.
-愛瑞絲  -別說對不起
- Iris-- - Don't say that you're sorry.
我知道你有歉意
Okay, I know that you are.
我不明白的是你到底怎么了
What I don't know is what is going on with you.
我們在同一個屋檐下長大
We grew up one bedroom down from each other.
你真的以為我不知道你開心的樣子嗎
Do you honestly think that I don't know when you're happy?
或傷心  沮喪  迷失時的樣子嗎
Or sad or depressed or lost?
我再問你最后一次  巴里·艾倫
I'm gonna ask you one last time, Barry Allen,
你最好老實回答我
and you better be honest with me.
你到底...
What the--
你想知道我發生了什么事
You want to know what's happening.
我現在能高速移動
I'm fast now.
天吶  我很想告訴你
God, I just want to tell you.
我的感受
How I feel.
我對你的感覺
How you make me feel.
但是我不能說
But I can't.
你到底是怎么回事
Hell is going on with you?
這個問題我們還沒說完
We are not done talking about this.
這是不可能的
That's impossible.
昨晚發生了一起謀殺案
There was a murder last night.
這些皮膚細胞屬于兇手的
These skin cells belong to the murderer,
但這些都是初始細胞
but these cells are naive.
他們可以復制這些干細胞
Stem cells that they can replicate
分析完成
變成身體所需的任何細胞
and become any cell the body needs.
這些只有嬰兒身上才會有
They only come from babies.
意思說你的兇手是新生兒嗎
This means your killer is what, a newborn?
你真的認為有人要殺我嗎
You honestly think that someone wants to kill me?
我們還不確定  斯塔格先生  但是
Well, we're not sure, Mr. Stagg, but...
在你受邀出席的典禮上發生了持械搶劫
an event you were being honored at was robbed at gunpoint.
而你的安保主管今天早上被人謀殺了
And your head of security was found murdered this morning.
我是科學家  慈善家
I am a scientist and a philanthropist.
我們幾乎不是殺手的目標
We're not often the targets of assassins.
那這些訴訟案呢
Well... what about lawsuits?
你有大概二十起懸而未決的訴訟案
You got about 20 of those pending against you.
這是無法改變的事實  警探
It is a sad fact of life, Detective, that
當你賺了一大筆錢時
when you earn a lot of money,
人們認為可以來分一杯羹
people who haven't think they can take yours.
比如說這個人嗎
People like this guy, for example?
丹東·布萊克
Danton Black?
Danton Black.
貨物升降機
你把他解雇了  現在他要起訴你
You fired him. Now he's suing you.
很遺憾  我們的工作關系沒能繼續下去
Unfortunately, our working relationship wasn't successful,
但是我可以向你們保證一件事
but I can assure you both of one thing.
丹東·布萊克
Danton Black...
不是一個殺手
is not a killer.
他是名臨床研究員  不是罪犯
He's a clinical researcher, not a criminal mastermind.
如果還有需要幫忙的地方  請聯系我
Now, if I can help you in any way, please let me know.
我和你們一樣  希望這些人盡快繩之以法
I want these people caught as much as you.
那就來吧
Then here we are!
趴下
Down!
隊長  發生了什么事
Captain, what's going on?
晚點和你說  巴里
Not now, Barry.
一名武裝槍手正在斯塔格工業制造騷亂
An armed gunman is shooting up Stagg Industries.
喬在那里
Joe's there.
把他帶出去  我來掩護你
Get him out of here. I'll cover you.
準備好了嗎  快走
Ready? Go.
快走
Go!
不
No.
不管你是誰  趕快投降吧
Whoever you are, give yourself up.
抱歉
Sorry.
我們哪也不去
We are not going anywhere.
除非西蒙·斯塔格死了
Until Simon Stagg is dead.
抱歉
Sorry.
這些擦傷已經快速愈合了
The abrasions are already rapidly healing.
是啊  我毫無還擊能力
Yeah, I got my ass handed to me.
你把血都弄到這套衣服上了
You got blood on my suit.
有一些應該是屬于兇手的
I think some of it belongs to him.
又是一個不友善的超能力者
Another not-so-friendly meta-human.
丹東·布萊克
Danton Black.
生物遺傳學家  專門研究治療性克隆
He's a bio-geneticist specialized in therapeutic cloning.
形成新器官  代替壞死的舊器官
Growing new organs to replace failing ones.
顯然是斯塔格偷了他的成果并解雇了他
Apparently Stagg stole his research and then fired him.
我看到斯塔格能自我復制
I saw Black create duplicates from his own body.
真是諷刺
That's pretty ironic.
這人專門研究克隆
The guy specialized in cloning
現在他可以復制自身
and now he can make xeroxes of himself.
如果他在用自己做實驗
If he was experimenting on himself
當他接觸到粒子加速器爆炸
when he was exposed to the dark matter wave
所投放的暗物質波
released by the particle accelerator explosion--
來看看這位克隆隊長
Meet captain clone.
別擔心  我會再想個更帥氣的名字
Don't worry. I'll come up with something cooler.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
喬說得對
Joe was right.
我被超能力沖昏了頭腦
I'm in way over my head.
我的速度是快  但我不是戰士
Yeah, I'm fast, but I am no warrior.
我一個超能力者都打不過  更別說六個了
Man, I could barely fight one meta-human, let alone six.
巴里
Barry.
我明白
I understand.
今天你失敗了
Today was a setback.
但是每項偉大的事業都會經歷挫折
But any grand enterprise has them.
不墜機幾次  我們也無法飛上天空
And we can never learn to fly without crashing a few times.
這不是偉大的事業  威爾斯博士
This wasn't a grand enterprise, Dr. Wells.
這是個錯誤
This was a mistake.
爸
Dad!
抱歉  不能有肢體接觸
Sorry. No physical contact.
五分鐘  艾倫
Five minutes, Allen.
坐下吧  兒子
Sit down, son.
巴里  你怎么到這里來的
Barry, how did you get here?
我跑來的  喬不肯帶我
I ran here. Joe wouldn't bring me.
-他不讓我見你  我恨他  -別別
- He wouldn't let me see you. I hate him. - No, no.
別這么說
Don't--don't say that.
不是喬不想讓你來
It isn't Joe that doesn't want you to come here.
是我不想讓你過來
I don't want you to come here.
我不想讓你看到我這個樣子
I don't want you to see me like this.
你必須得放了他
You have to let him go.
我爸爸沒有做那些事
My dad didn't do these things.
他沒有傷害我媽媽
He didn't hurt my mom.
是閃電里的那個人
It was the man in the lightning.
閃電人殺了我媽媽
The lightning man killed my mom.
-巴里  看著我  -不是我爸爸
- Barry, look at me. - Not my dad.
看著我
Look at me.
你幫不了我
You can't help me.
明白嗎  喬會在我出去之前照顧你
Okay? Now Joe's gonna look after you until I can get out of here.
你只要繼續當爸爸媽媽的乖孩子就好了
You just be the good boy that your mom and I know you are.
爸爸
Dad?
警探  持槍人被控制住了嗎
Detective, was the gunman apprehended?
槍手目前位置尚不明確
The shooter's whereabouts are unknown at this time.
英雄警察拯救斯塔格總裁
我們認為他持有武器并且極度危險
We consider him armed and extremely dangerous.
謝謝  問題到此結束
Thank you. No more questions.
干得不錯  艾迪
Nice work, Eddie.
天時地利而已
Nah. Right place, right time.
不  你是今日的英雄
No, you were a hero today.
還有一個殺手沒被中城警局逮捕
CCPD still has a killer on the loose.
我得回警局了
I should get back to the precinct.
你來這里是為了喝杯咖啡
So did you come here for caffeine,
還是為了來告訴我你到底怎么了
or are you finally gonna tell me what's going on with you?
斯塔格先生
Mr. Stagg,
我希望您重新考慮保護性監禁的事情
I wish you would reconsider our offer for protective custody.
丹東·布萊克殺人不眨眼
Danton Black has proven he is willing to kill,
而且他還有些  朋友
and he's got... friends.
相信我  他們都很危險
And trust me, they're all dangerous.
我增強了保衛  警探
I've increased my security, detective.
我倒希望布萊克來找麻煩
I hope Black comes looking for trouble.
因為他會發現麻煩很大
'Cause he'll find plenty.
說話真像一位慈善家
Spoken like a true philanthropist.
還是人道主義者來的
or is it humanitarian?
抱歉  我總是記不住
I'm sorry. I can never remember
你正在假扮的身份是什么  西蒙
which one you're pretending to be, Simon.
哈里森
Harrison...
不用起身了
Don't get up.
又是你的粉絲嗎  博士
Another fan of yours, doctor?
我們能談談嗎  警探
Can we talk, detective?
這么說你是對的了
So you were right.
巴里不是唯一的特殊人物
Barry's not the only one who's special.
今天這個想殺西蒙·斯塔格的人  可以
This guy that tried to kill Simon Stagg today, he could--
不斷地自我復制
Replicate spontaneously.
我們知道了
Yeah, we know.
你知道巴里的事嗎
Did you know about Barry?
當他剛進入昏迷時
When he was first in his coma
你來到醫院  詢問我
you came to the hospital, and you asked me
是否能夠把他帶到尖端科研實驗室去
if you could take him to S.T.A.R. Labs.
你那時知道他的能力嗎
Did you know what he could do?
我當時懷疑他已經被...
I had my suspicions that he was...
影響了
affected.
喬
Hey, Joe...
我從沒有想成為某個
I was never looking to become the senior member
秘密犯罪打擊小組的長老人物
of a secret crime fighting unit.
你和我都清楚
You and I both know
我們才是保護中城的真材實料
we are the only ones equipped to protect Central City.
也許我更想要保護巴里
Maybe I'm more interested in protecting Barry.
當然了  他已經被教育好
But of course he's all set to fly
與你一同赴湯蹈火
into the fire right along with you.
不  他沒有
No, he's not.
不再是了  他退出了
Not anymore. He quit.
他沒告訴你嗎
He didn't tell you?
我還沒見到他
I haven't seen him.
我肯定只是暫時的
Well I'm sure it's only temporary.
以我對巴里的了解來看
From what I know of Barry,
當他自己決定了什么事
when he sets his mind to something...
就沒人能夠說服他了
No one's gonna talk him out of it.
但是下一次他穿起戰袍
But the next time he suits up...
直奔危險之處時
runs headlong into danger...
他會失敗
he will fail.
為什么呢
Why?
他不認為自己有能力
He doesn't think he's capable.
疑惑
Doubt...
才是他真正的敵人
is his real enemy.
喬  不管外邊發生了什么
Joe, not whatever's lurking out there.
只要你繼續在質疑他
And as long as you continue to doubt him,
他就會繼續自我疑惑下去
he'll keep doubting himself.
而且順便一提
And for the record...
我也關心他
I care about him, too.
看起來你真餓了
Guess you were hungry.
緩解壓力吧
Stress eating.
我是來道歉的
I came to say I'm sorry.
你是對的  我是有些冷漠
And you're right. I have been distant.
-沒錯  -像個混蛋
- Correct. - Kind of a jerk.
你應該多道道歉
You should apologize more often.
你挺會煽情的
You are really sensational at it.
那么  那天你想和我說什么來的
So... what were you going to tell me the other day?
我覺得我得做件事
I thought I had to do something.
做件我覺得很重要的事
Something I thought was important,
但是結果發現我對那事并不在行
but it turns out that I'm not very good at it.
可我對做你朋友很在行
But what I am good at is being your friend.
所以如果你需要我幫忙
So if you need help coming up with
-給你找個新話題來寫  -我有一個了
- a new topic for your article-- - I found one.
我找到了一件讓我特別感興趣的事
Something that actually interests me.
我知道這聽起來有些瘋狂
I know this is gonna sound crazy...
這周網上把這事都傳瘋了
it's been all over the internet this week.
在大樓失火時
At a building fire...
銀行被打劫時
at a bank heist...
還有那晚那些劫匪
even the other night when those robbers
紅色尾跡
開槍射擊保安時
shot at the security guard,
那保安說他被快速地轉移到了外面
he said he was whooshed outside.
有什么在救這些人
Something out there is saving people.
我以為你想寫的是新聞
I thought you were taking journalism,
不是科幻小說
not science fiction writing.
從我認識你開始
Ever since I have known you
你就一直堅信一切皆有可能
you have believed in the impossible.
如果你沒有說錯呢
What if you were right?
也許你母親去世那晚的事你說的是對的呢
What if you were right about the night that your mom died?
尖端科研實驗室
我說了  我不干了
Look, I told you I'm through.
我知道  但你得來一趟尖端科研實驗室
I know, but you need to get to S.T.A.R. Labs
馬上
right now.
-巴里  沒事的  -怎么可能沒事
- Barry, it's okay. - It is not okay.
布萊克在這  而他就只是站著
Black is here, and he's just... standing there.
這不是他吧
That's not him, is it?
這是他的一個復制品
It's one of his replicates.
你們怎么弄到的
How did you get it?
我培養出來的
I grew him.
我從你衣服上分離出了布萊克的血樣
I isolated a sample of Black's blood from you suit
試著能不能觸發體外培養機制
to see if I could trigger the in vitro cultivation process
以便研究布萊克的增殖
and learn how Black multiplies.
所以我把靶細胞嫁接上了蛋白凝膠
So I exposed the target cells to a protein gel,
結果它們開始自我復制
and they began replicating...
成了這樣
into that.
他為什么
Why isn't he...
它為什么不動
it doing anything?
我們做了一個大腦掃描
We did a brain scan.
只有無意識運動機制有活動  別無其他
Involuntary motor functions are active, little else.
我們認為它只是個接受器
We think it's acting as a receiver.
沒有布萊克  克隆體只是空殼
The clones are an empty shell without Black.
只要打倒真的布萊克
Shut down the real Black,
可能就能一次打倒所有克隆體
and you might shut them all down.
但我們怎么知道哪個是真的丹東·布萊克呢
But how do we know which one's the real Danton Black?
我是因為你自己出現的昏迷才想到的
That occurred to me given your own passing out.
布萊克的能力有限制  就像你一樣
Black has limits, just like you.
要控制所有克隆體
Controlling all of those clones
肯定要消耗巨大的體力
must require a tremendous amount of physical strength.
所以顯示出疲憊虛弱的跡象的那個
So, look for the one showing signs of weakness or fatigue.
就是本體
He's the prime.
這只是個理論
Just a theory...
但你也許愿意實踐一下  艾倫先生
but one you might want to put to the test, Mr. Allen.
還有  我做了這些高卡路里蛋白塊
Plus, I whipped up these high-calorie protein bars
以便你能維持新陳代謝
for you to keep your metabolism up.
還有其他的嗎
Any more of them?
沒了
Nope.
它怎么突然動了
Why did it start moving?
是本體
The prime.
我想應該是本體下了命令
My guess is, the prime is on the move.
它也收到了戰斗的召喚
This one heard the summons to battle.
而我知道它們正被召喚去哪里
And I know where he was summoned to.
斯塔格工業
Stagg industries.
那趕緊呼叫警員啊
You should call it in.
警方沒法對付此事
Police can't fight this.
像馬登一樣  布萊克的能力
What Black's become, like Mardon...
我應付不了
beyond me.
警方應該也應付不了
Maybe way beyond them, too.
唯一一個能應付的人
The only person it's not beyond
就是你
is you.
你需要這么做  我明白
You gotta do this. I get it.
所以就這一次  你就聽我一句話吧
So for once in your life, do what I tell you to do.
去阻止他
Go stop him.
斯塔格工業
明早把結果給我  行嗎
Just get me those figures by morning, okay?
站住  不許動
Freeze. Don't move.
你好  丹東
Hello, Danton.
再見  西蒙
Goodbye, Simon.
待在這兒
Stay here.
我知道斯塔格偷了你的研究成果
I know Stagg stole your research,
但即使如此  你也無權殺人
but that doesn't give you the right to murder.
你以為我就是為了工作復仇嗎
You think this is about my job.
我是為了伊麗莎白
This is about Elizabeth.
我的妻子
She was my wife.
她患上了冠狀動脈退化
She had a degenerative coronary disease.
已經在移植名單上許多年了  但是
She'd been on the transplant list for years, but...
她沒有時間了
time was running out.
所以我既然沒法兒給她弄到新的心臟
So if I couldn't get her a new heart...
你就想給她培植一個
You were gonna grow her one.
我馬上就要成功了
I was so close.
可是斯塔格偷走了我的研究
Until Stagg stole my research.
就為了能獲得榮譽
So he could reap the glory.
而我只能眼看著最好的朋友死去
And I got to bury my best friend.
現在
Now...
我已經孤家寡人了
I'm alone.
記住  巴里  找到本體
Remember, Barry. Find the prime.
他們人太多了
There's too many of them to fight.
巴里  你必須要孤立本體
Barry, you need to isolate the prime.
我做不到  這根本就不可能
I can't. It's impossible.
一切皆有可能  巴里  你教我的
Nothing's impossible, Barry. You taught me that.
你做得到
You can do this.
巴里
Barry.
巴里  你沒事吧
Barry, are you all right?
我沒事
I'm fine.
結束了
It's done.
堅持住
Hang on!
不
No!
別
Don't.
中城警務人員現在確認了
Central city police officials are now confirming
-前雇員丹東·布萊克  -我試圖拯救他
- former employee Danton Black-- - Tried to save him.
他不想被拯救
Doesn't sound like he wanted to be saved.
有些人  一旦受傷了...
Some people, when they break...
就再也無法復原
They can't be put together again.
有些人卻在治愈后更強大
Some people heal even stronger.
我希望如此
I hope so.
至少多元體
Well, at least Multiplex
不能再傷害任何人
won't be able to hurt anyone else.
我告訴過你我會想到很酷的名字
Told you I'd come up with a cool name.
我也許是那個穿著英雄服奔跑的人...
Yeah, I may be the one in the suit doing all the running...
但當我在外面幫助人
but when I'm out there helping people,
改變世界時
making a difference...
你們與我同在
you're all out there with me.
我終于搞明白了一點
Finally realized something,
我們都被那次的閃電擊中了
we were all struck by that lightning.
肚子餓了嗎
Hungry?
意大利辣香腸  橄欖...還有墨西哥辣椒
Pepperoni, olives... and jalapenos.
我想你應該會喜歡
Just like you like it.
謝謝
Thank you.
你搞錯了
You were wrong.
這周我搞錯了很多事
I have been wrong a lot this week.
你得說得更明確一點
You're gonna have to be more specific.
你說你一直被
You said that one of things driving you
不能幫助你爸爸的事困擾著
to run around out there was that you couldn't help your dad.
你可以幫他
You can help him.
我們可以
We can.
我們會找出
We're gonna figure out
那晚殺害你母親的人或東西
who or what killed your mother that night.
然后讓你爸父親免受牢獄之災
And then we're gonna get your father out of prison.
我們一起
Together.
喬  之前我說你不是我的父親...
Joe, what I said about you not being my father--
巴里  我知道
Barry, I know.
我知道我不是你的父親
I know I'm not your father.
你說得對  你不是
You're right. You're not.
你只是...那個讓我吃得飽
You're just... the man who kept me fed
和穿得暖的人...
and in clothes...
每晚坐在我床邊等我睡著
who sat beside my bed at night until I fell asleep
因為我怕黑...
because I was afraid of the dark...
教導我寫作業...
helped me with my homework...
教我如何開車和刮胡子...
you taught me how to drive and shave...
還把我送去上大學
and you dropped me off at college.
對于我你做了很多父親會做的事
Sounds a lot like a dad to me.
每個小孩都夢想當超級英雄
Every kid dreams of being a superhero.
擁有能力  拯救人類
Having powers. Saving people.
但沒有孩子想到當自己是英雄
But no kid thinks about what it's like when you're a hero
卻無法拯救人類時會怎樣
and you're not saving people.
事實是...
Truth is...
其他的都沒怎么改變
not much else changes.
你還是會痛  你還是會愛
You still hurt. You still love.
你還是會許愿期待以及害怕
You still wish and hope and fear things.
紅色尾跡的新消息
紅色尾跡出現在中城街道上
被紅色尾跡從火災中救出的家庭
紅色尾跡又在中城出現了
你還是需要別人陪你度過這一切
And you still need people to help you with all of it.
某種程度上  那才是最美好之處
In some ways, that's the best part.
巴里  有輛裝甲車在格里芬大街被劫持了
Barry, an armored car was just hijacked on Griffin Avenue.
你馬上趕過去
Get your ass over there.
收到  其實...
I got it. Actually...
最美好之處
The best part?
是這個
It's this.
好吧...
Wells...
是誰讓你進來的
Who the hell let you in here?
你在外邊搞了場派對嗎
You been having a party out there?
我想你已經看過電視新聞了
I'm sure you saw on TV.
我的一個前雇員試圖殺死我
A former employee of mine tried to kill me.
有復制能力的前雇員...
Former employee with the ability to replicate...
跟能極速移動的人對峙
faced off against a man who could move at super speed.
你也看見他了  不是嗎
You've seen him too, haven't you?
沒錯  看見了
Indeed, I have.
超凡的能力
Extraordinary.
他擁有的能力  就像...
The power he possesses, it's like the--
就像古代的神
it's like the gods of old.
就像地球上的神
it's like Mercury on earth.
你能想象如果你能控制他的能力嗎
Can you imagine if you could control his power?
如果你能...如果你能駕馭它
If you could--if you could harness it?
你可能能改變人類的意義
You could change what it means to be human.
戴著紅色面具的人是關鍵
The man in a red mask is the key,
我要抓住他
and I'm gonna get him.
戴著紅色面具的人
The man in the red mask.
他叫閃電俠
He's called the flash.
至少這么說...
Or at least...
他有一天會成為閃電俠
He will be one day.
搞什么鬼
What the hell?
原諒我  西蒙
Forgive me, Simon.
我擔心你會以為我是針對你
I worry you think that you will think this is personal,
其實不是
and it's not.
是為了那個戴著紅色面具的人...
It's just that the man in the red mask...
世界上最快的人...
the fastest man alive...
必須確保他的...
he must be kept...
安全
safe.